I got to tell you, Rick.
It's pretty great
to be in this spaceship,
just the two of us, you know?
Just cruising around,
Rick and Morty style.
I agree, Morty.
[ Belches ]
It's nice to get
back to the basics
after a pretty intense,
mixed-bag of a year.
-Ohh!
-Relax.
That's what windshields
are for.
I didn't know that there were
bugs out in space.
Well, w-what did you think,
Morty?
Life just developed
on earth by itself?
Here, let me
take care of this.
Geez, Rick,
that's disgusting.
I don't want
to look at that.
Yeah, guess
I'm out of fluid.
L-let me find
a place to stop.
Hey, muchacho, does your planet
have wiper fluid yet,
or are you gonna freak out
and start worshipping us?
The general store
ought to have what you need.
Thanks.
Of course, you'll be wanting
to be gone from here by sundown.
Yeah, sure thing.
Wait a minute. What? Why?
Sundown is when
the festival begins.
The festival?
Ooh, well, for millennia,
our society has been free
of crime and war,
-living in perfect peace.
-Oh, I know what this is!
You've been able
to sustain world peace
because you have one night
a year where you all run around
robbing and murdering each other
without consequence.
-That's right.
-What?!
It's like "the purge," Morty.
That movie "the purge"?
Oh, have you
been here before?
No, no, but I've been to a few
planets with the same gimmick.
You know, sometimes it's called
the cleansing or the red time.
There was this one world that
called it just murder night.
I-it's a purge planet.
They're peaceful, and then,
you know, they just purge.
T-that's horrible!
Yeah.
You want to check it out?
♪
[ Electricity crackling ]
So, what do you do
during the festival?
You lock yourself in,
or you go out and do some stuff?
Oh, I do
some pretty bad stuff.
Oh, I bet you do, old timer.
[ Laughs ]
Gee-- Rick, come on.
The sun is setting.
W-we got to
get out of here.
All right, well, w-what do I
owe you for the wiper fluid?
It's on the house.
Oh, and, uh,
why -- why don't you have
some candy bars, as well?
Oh, no way.
That's really nice of you.
I'm a nice guy...
For now.
[ Chuckling ]
Ohh, I don't doubt it.
-Rick!
-Yeah, yeah.
Hey, have a good festival,
old timer.
I intend to.
Rick, unlock it!
Just a second, Morty.
Oh, look at that sunset.
Stop screwing around.
[ Click ]
There we go. Much better.
Now we can see.
Great.
Hey, you know what, Morty?
Why don't we christen our
squeaky-clean windshield here
by watching a little
of this purge through it?
What?! No!
What is your problem?!
Morty, grow up.
If you don't want to watch,
don't watch,
but, you know, it's my car.
[ Belches ] Also, if you tell
your mom about this,
-I'll purge you.
-You're the worst.
And this planet is the worst.
How can you be into this?
You know, people are gonna
kill each other.
So, what, y-y-you trying
to sit here and tell me that
[belches] I-if -- if there's
a video online
with someone getting
decapitated,
-you don't click on it?
-No!
Why -- why would I do that?
You do that?
I don't,
because it would bore me.
I see [Bleep] like that
for breakfast, Morty.
But if you don't do it,
I say it's because
you're afraid of your own
primal instincts.
So you stuff them down and --
[ Bell chiming ]
Oh, oh!
Shh. Shh. It's starting.
-Oh-ho-ho! Here we go.
-I'm not watching.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
your medal's in the mail.
-I'm gonna get a closer look.
-Oh, okay, sure.
And then someone's
gonna throw a rock
and hit the car
and then we're gonna crash
and we're gonna
be stuck down there
and it's gonna be
what we deserve.
Yawn.
Whoa!
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Whoa, they are purging
the [Bleep] out of each other.
[ Muffled screaming ]
Oh, my God!
Oh [Bleep]
That was --
okay, yeah. T-that was gross.
Wow. Man, I think my eyes
were bigger than my stomach
on this one, Morty.
Ugh.
My appetite for purge-spectating
got filled pretty quick.
Oh, God.
[ Grunts ]
[ Retching ]
[ Woman screaming ]
Get away from me!
No! No! Help!
Somebody help me! Aah!
All right, Morty.
L-let's get out of here.
Wait, wait, wait. Hold on.
W-we have to go down there.
[ Belching ]
What? Why?
That poor girl.
W-we have to save her.
Uh, Morty, in space,
we have something we call
the non-interference policy.
We got the wiper fluid.
We watched them kill each other.
We're leaving.
Help me save that girl, or I'm
telling mom you brought me here.
You little turd.
[ Screaming ]
Please! Leave me alone!
Leave you alone?
During a purge?
I don't think so, baby.
It's okay.
We're not gonna hurt you.
My name is Morty.
This is my grandpa.
-We're tourists.
-Not anymore.
-Aah!
Oh, my God.
This is [Bleep] awesome!
Morty, this is really cool.
Hey, y-you want to help me out
here and kill some people?
It's fun.
We're totally justified
because we're saving
a little girl.
I mean, w-w-we're both free and
clear to murder these people.
-Are you okay?
-Yes.
I have to find
somewhere to hide.
Well, you can hide with us.
Rick?
-Yeah?
-Do you think we could take --
-w-what's your name?
-Arthrisha.
Could we take arthrisha
up in the ship
and, you know,
just wait out the purge?
Oh, Morty, how can I refuse
after all you've done
to blackmail me?
Your vehicle --
is it from the gods?
-No.
-Yes.
So, uh, you know,
when the purge started,
did people get into it
right away,
or were they like,
"wait, what?
This is gonna stop crime
how, exactly?"
Yeah, it took some time
for people to accept it.
Yeah, I bet. [ Chuckles ]
I bet.
Yeah, it's kind of like
cellphones, you know?
At first,
everyone was like,
"look at those
douchebags purging,"
and then
the next thing you know,
they're like,
"it's just so convenient."
Geez, you working on
your tight five
for the comedy store,
Morty?
Whatcha doing?
Watching some TV,
playing on your phone?
-Is that a real question?
-Just making conversation.
Are you? What part of that
gives me anything to work with?
My choice is to say nothing,
be sarcastic,
or bark "yes"
like a trained animal.
It's not a conversation.
You're holding me
verbally hostage.
Okay, ass-face.
I'll go in the kitchen.
-Hey, dad.
-Yeah?
Whatcha doing?
Going into the kitchen?
Okay.
-Yeah, you like that?
-Screw you.
So, uh, do most people
wear masks when they purge?
I-I don't want to answer
any more purge questions.
All right,
hey, hey, that's cool.
I can roll with that.
[ Blowing raspberries ]
-[ Gasps ] My Nana!
-Huh?
My Nana!
We have to save her!
You just now remembered
your Nana exists.
I-I was traumatized.
Haven't you been through
like 15 purges?
I mean, some as a child?
Will somebody
just help me get her?
Fine, whatever.
Morty, stay.
Oh, God. Oh, crap. Oh, crap!
-Get out! Get out!
-Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Get the [Bleep] out
of the flying machine!
Oh, my God!
O-okay! Okay!
-Back up, asshole.
-[ Whimpers ]
-Back up.
-Ohh.
-Back the [Bleep] up!
-Aah!
For what it's worth,
I'm sorry,
but that's not really
worth anything tonight, is it?
Y-you can't leave us here.
You're killing us!
You hear me? Come back.
Y-you got to come back.
Change your mind.
Oh, geez.
Morty! Aah!
[Bleep] Amish bitch shot me!
[ Grunts ]
She tried to purge me, Morty.
You let your wiener do
the walking, and now I'm dead.
-Rick, she took the car!
-You [Bleep] kidding me, Morty?!
She took my car
and the gun.
We're like the rest
of these assholes now.
W-w-we're gonna
get purged, Morty.
Help me up.
Oh, geez, geez!
Wait a minute, Rick.
Why don't we just use
your portal gun?
It's in the car, dip-ass.
[ Grunts ]
Oh, God, it hurts.
She got me right in
the goddamn liver, Morty.
It's the hardest-working liver
in the galaxy, Morty,
and now it has a hole in it.
I hope it was worth it.
I was just trying
to do right.
Yeah, well, that's not really
the theme of tonight's party.
Heads up. Rapists.
Well, don't just stand there,
Morty.
-Purge 'em.
-Me?
No, me. Should I rub
my liver hole on them?
Pick up a stick or something
and kill them.
-Um, w-we come in peace.
-[ Screaming ]
Oh, my God.
[ Grunts ]
There's more
where that came from!
You want to get purged,
you bring it!
Drop [Belches] drop your shit!
Drop it all.
Morty, go get their shit.
Hurry up.
I only had one
of those things I threw.
I'm holding a box of tic tacs
right now.
-Want some crackers?
-No, thank you.
Are you ready
to be nice to me?
In exchange
for crackers?
-What happened to you?
-Dad, get a job.
You're trying to create drama
because you're bored.
Oh.
[ Beeping, whirring ]
It's the space phone
grandpa gave us.
-Hello?
-Hey, Summer, it's grandpa.
I need you
to do me a favor.
-I can barely hear you.
-Who is it?
Morty and I are on a planet
that's purging.
-I need you to take down --
-a plan that's what?
We're on a planet
that's purging, Summer. Purging.
We lost our car and my gun,
and we're in a purge.
-Ooh, is it taddi Mason?
-Like the movie "the purge"?
Yes, I-I need you
to take --
-that movie sucked.
-Oh, my God. Hold on.
It's not taddi Mason?
Dad, who the [Bleep]
is taddi Mason?
-My friend.
-Aah!
Are you okay?
I'm putting you on speaker.
-Taddi?
-Yes, Jerry, it's taddi,
a person no one's ever heard of
until now,
calling you
on a space phone.
I can't tell
if you're being sarcastic.
[ Growls ]
Aah!
[ Growling ]
[ Gunshots ]
Reload, fast.
Summer, w-we need you
to take down this number.
-Quit screwing around.
-Morty? Are you all right?
-No!
-Why are you with taddi Mason?
Holy [Bleep] dad!
Shut the [Bleep] up!
Okay. I guess I'm just this
entire family's toilet paper.
Are you writing this down?
Will you please write this down?
-Summer: Yes, yes.
-7-7-1-9-8...
[ Growling ]
...3-6-4-2-1-1-2-5.
Aah!
[ Growling ]
You son of a bitch!
Morty, I don't want to be
the "a little help" guy,
but a little help?
-Aah!
-Okay, I have a pen. Go.
7-7-1-9-8-3-
6-4-2-1-1-2-5.
A spoon, Morty?
-A spoon?!
-I'm sorry.
There's a pile of silverware
next to you,
and you throw me the one thing
that can never kill anything?
All right, okay!
Summer, on the shelf above
my workbench in the garage,
there's a red box
with a keypad on it.
You're gonna
take that box outside,
and you're gonna type the number
I just gave you into the keypad.
-Got it?
-Got it.
Is it just part of growing up
to hate your dad?
I'm ignoring you.
Morty, if I can get to the top
of that lighthouse,
I can send the beacon, and your
sister can launch our package.
Just remember,
if there's people in there
and they try to purge us,
we got to purge them first.
We're not purging anyone, Rick,
all right? W-will you stop it?
Morty, if we're gonna
survive tonight,
you're gonna need to harness
your repressed rage.
I don't have any!
Spoken like a person
with repressed rage.
[ Doorbell rings ]
I take no part
in the festival.
If you desire to kill me,
I only ask you do it quickly.
No such agenda, chief.
We're not too keen on the purge,
either, sir.
We were just hoping to get
on the roof of your lighthouse
so we can send a beacon
to my sister on earth.
-It's a different planet.
-By the way,
life on other planets exists.
Don't let it distract you.
I'll let you use my lighthouse
for shelter and beacon-sending
on the condition that you listen
to my tale.
-Okay.
-Deal.
All right, I'm gonna go
to the roof and set things up.
-Morty, you listen to his tale.
-Okay.
[ Clears throat ]
"Fade in. Exterior.
Unnamed city. Day.
The hustle and bustle
is a symphony of progress.
We pan past windows, each of
which contain a different story,
to find jacey lakims, 28 --
hot, but doesn't know it.
Jacey stops
when her high heel gets caught
in the grating of a sewer.
Suddenly, a man steps into frame
and points a gun at her.
This is not her day.
Fade to black.
Title -- 'three weeks earlier.'"
[ sighs ] You really don't want
to talk to me about this.
Dad, grandpa and Morty
are in danger.
You're unemployed,
and you're bored.
-They're a higher priority.
-Stop saying I'm unemployed!
Okay, 7-7-1-9-8-3-6-4-2-1-1
2 -- aah!
Good lord! Now what?
[ Whirring, humming ]
Look, I'm your father, and
I love you is all I'm saying.
-I'll leave it at that.
-Fine, dad!
[ Both scream ]
Oh, he might have said
to take it outside.
Rick:
Come on, Summer.
How hard is it
to type some numbers into a box?
Target locked.
[ Device beeps ]
Oh, thank God.
Well, I did my job.
Summer did her job.
Now all Morty has to do is
finish listening to that tale.
"Blane: Maybe I don't need
a new friend.
Jacey: Maybe you're
the only friend I need.
Blane: Need, or want?
Jacey: I've never been much
for wanting.
Blane: Spoken like someone
with needs."
-Oh, geez.
-Hmm?
Uh, sorry.
K-keep going.
"Jacey reaches out
and touches his face.
It's clear he needs
what she wants.
She's a woman.
He's a man.
The city burns in the background
as he takes her in his arms.
Fade out.
Title -- 'the end'...
Question mark."
-Wow.
-Yeah?
It's...
G-good job. Good job.
-You liked it?
-Of course I did.
You didn't laugh
at the scene in the bar.
I...Thought it was funny,
but I wanted to hear the rest.
Do you have any thoughts?
Notes?
No. I-I just enjoyed it.
That's my note, you know?
Please write more.
-Seems a little insincere.
-What? No.
You don't have to
mollycoddle me.
I want to improve my writing.
Tell me your real thoughts.
All right. Well, um,
I'm not a huge fan, personally,
of the whole "three weeks
earlier" teaser thing.
I feel like, you know,
we should start our stories
where they begin
not start them
where they get interest--
-get out.
-Um, what?
No, I'm sick of this.
You bang on my door,
you beg me to help you, I share
something personal with you,
and you take
a giant shit on it.
Hey, man, we asked
if we could put up a beacon --
well, you can't.
I want you out of here.
You're a petty person,
and you're insecure,
and you're taking it out on me.
That's a good script.
What the hell?!
I don't care.
I want you out.
-What?
-Take that thing down.
Your grandson
is a shitty person. Leave now.
-Morty!
-Rick, I didn't do anything.
I sat through
his entire screenplay --
you "sat through it"?
Yes! Did you want me
to weep with joy?
-It's terrible!
-Whoa! Morty! We're guests here.
I tried to be a good guest!
He dragged it out of me!
-I'm taking down this beacon.
-No, stop! That's not fair!
Just because
you hate your own writing
doesn't make me
a bad person!
Aah!
You like that? You want me
to cut to three weeks earlier
when you were alive?
Whoa, Morty.
You just purged.
Beacon arriving.
[ Device beeps ]
Okay, time to go.
-Well, terrific.
-[ Sighs ]
Dad, what's going on?
What's the deal here?
I just wanted to spend some time
with my daughter.
You're growing up so fast.
-You used to be my little girl.
-[ Chuckles ] Yeah.
Remember when we used to
go to the playground,
and I'd push you
on the swings?
Oh, you could push me higher
than all the other kids.
You were so small
and cute.
I thought you were gonna fly
right off into the street.
[ Chuckling ]
I used to pee my pants.
I know,
and now look at you!
You have a job.
You're making really good money.
You're not paying any rent,
so you have plenty
of disposable income.
Oh, God, dad.
Please, don't.
I just need
a few hundred dollars
to get through the month. I have
some interviews coming up.
Something's gonna come through.
I can feel it.
I'm going inside.
[ Door shuts ]
[ Sighs ] I guess this is what
rock bottom feels like, Jerry.
Ow!
It's okay, Morty.
It's the purge, you know?
Pushing old lighthouse keepers
down the stairs is totally cool.
It's not cool, Rick.
I-I'm not like these people.
I can't run around chopping
people's heads off
one day a year and then
sleep well the rest of the time.
Well, you better start getting
used to it, little bitch,
because we got
some [Bleep] company.
Hey, there he is.
Here I am.
[ Beacon whirring ]
Morty.
Time to [Belches] purge.
[ Gunfire, screaming ]
[ Tony! Toni! Toné!'S
"feels good" plays ]
[ Screaming ]
♪ it feels good
♪ yeah
♪ holdin' you so
♪ it feels good
geez. Wow, Morty.
Now you're getting into it.
Never expected that
out of you.
All right, uh,
let's go find my ship.
Hey, hey, Morty, Morty. There
it is down there -- my ship.
It looks to me like the...
Morty?
[ Gunfire ]
Suck my [Bleep]
♪ it feels good
eat this!
Ooh, boy,
you're really, uh...
Ha-ha! Ha!
♪ it feels good
you're really going for it
over there, huh?
I, uh [Belches] I think,
uh [Belches]
I think those people
were just hiding.
I don't give a [Bleep]
[ Gunfire ]
Okay, Morty, now you're just
shooting corpses.
-How do you like this?
-Okay, buddy.
All right. That's good.
Good job.
[ Screams ]
Time to go home.
[ Weapon charging ]
Wait, stop!
Please, don't kill me!
I-I never intended to harm you,
I swear.
I am trying to end the festival.
-W-w-what do you mean?
-I was going to use your ship
to destroy the rich assholes
that run our society
and save my people from the
horrors of this yearly festival.
[Bleep] That, Rick! We got to
kill her! Kill her! Kill her!
Whoa! Geez, Morty,
purge it down a little.
"Purge! Don't purge!"
You're sending me
mixed messages, Rick.
Morty [Belches]
you're acting like
a [Belches]
freaking lunatic.
-Calm down.
-Screw you, Rick!
I'll purge you, too,
you old, rickety piece of crap!
This has been
a long time coming!
I'm gonna rip
your [Bleep] guts out
and smear them
all over your face!
I ain't taking no sh--
-aah!
-Okay, s-sorry about that.
Now, where are
these rich people?
[ String quartet playing ]
[ Glass clinking ]
To another successful year
of the festival,
pitting poor people against each
other for thousands of years.
[ Tony! Toni! Toné!'S
"feels good" plays ]
Wait, w-where is that music
coming from?
What is the meaning of this?
♪ it feels good
here's the deal.
I'm not here to judge.
I'm just a guy
from another planet.
But this girl
is one of your poor people,
and I guess you guys
felt like it was okay
to subject her
to inhuman conditions
because there was no chance
of it ever hurting you.
It's sort of
the socio-political equivalent
of, say, a suit of power armor
around you.
But now things are evened out,
so, arthrisha?
[ All gasp ]
Happy festival [Bleep] suckers!
Suck my [Bleep]
chew my balls!
Suck my huge [Bleep]
Geez.
♪ it feels good
you want to get in on this,
Rick?
No, I really -- honestly,
I-I've had my fill.
It's gratuitous
at this point.
You sure you don't want
to join in?
This is really amazing.
♪ it feels good
yeah, but --
ah, all right.
[Bleep] It.
♪ It feels good
yeah, bitch, what's up?
♪ it feels good
♪ yeah
whoa!
♪ Ohh, it feels good
okay, now it's time
we do a little dancing
to -- to Tony! Toni! Toné!
♪ it feels good, yeah
look at my [Bleep] feet,
mother [Bleep]
Whoo! Aw, yeah!
♪ it feels good
arthrisha, what do you got?
Check this move out.
♪ oh, it feels good
[ belches ]
Oh, ho!
I don't know what song that is,
but I [Bleep] love it!
"Feels good."
It's a [Bleep] hit song.
♪ it feels good
topped the charts, I think.
Ho, ho!
♪ Oh, it feels good
[ rooster crows ]
Hey, thanks
for helping me, Rick.
You're a pretty great guy.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. [Bleep] You
for shooting my liver.
I'll see you around.
Oh, man.
What -- what happened?
Don't worry about it,
Morty.
Listen, if you wanted to try
to get a piece,
you better hurry up.
Now's your last chance.
Hey, hey, arthrisha,
um, maybe I could --
uh, I have a boyfriend.
-Okay.
-I'm not trying to be rude.
I just --
I don't want to lead you on.
I-I-I understand.
I mean, thank you so much
for helping end the festival,
but I have a boyfriend,
and, uh, he's just --
okay, okay,
you can stop saying it.
I took it okay
the first time,
and now you're just
repeating stuff.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-It's okay.
Oh, you're so sweet, I just --
oh, but I can't.
Yeah, you're still
doing it.
It won't be easy creating a new
society from the ground up.
Well, a helpful rule might be if
you need something, you get it.
-Pretty simple, right?
-I need food.
-Who's got food for that guy?
-I do, but this is for me.
Can't you make some more?
Oh, sure. And while
I'm making food for everyone,
who takes care of my kids?
I'll take care of your kids,
if I get some extra food for it.
Extra food?
Well, I'm not gonna do extra
work if we all get the same.
All right,
okay, fair is fair.
If you do extra work,
you get extra food.
Oh.
[ All murmuring ]
Who's gonna keep track
of who gets how much food
for how much work?
Hello. I can do that.
I'll keep track
of everyone's food,
you know,
in exchange for food.
That's not a real job!
Oh, and making food is?
You son of a bitch!
Eat this!
[ All screaming ]
Guys, guys, guys, guys,
whoa, whoa.
Cool it, now.
Take it easy.
There's too much
aggression here.
What if we designate
a period of time
during which we can all
get this hate, murder,
and rage out of our system --
I can't help
but feel ashamed
about what I did
back there, Rick.
I guess you were right. I've got
a lot of repressed stuff
-I need to deal with.
-Don't worry about it, Morty.
Remember
those candy bars earlier
-that we got in the first act?
-Yeah, what about them?
Turns out they have a chemical
in them called purgenol
that amplifies
all your violent tendencies.
Oh, boy. Whew!
Thank goodness for that, huh?
That's a relief.
Yep. Don't even sweat.
You're still
the same old Morty.
Your character's
totally protected.
♪ It feels good
♪
Man:
And there's the approach.
Jerry, what is
"taddi Mason llc,"
and why is
our phone bill $700?
Uh...
Hey, are you bored...
...Lonely, just looking
for a friend?
Uh...
Call me, taddi Mason.
It's only $1.99 a minute
to talk.
Uh...
Sign up today,
and I'll even call you
on a regular basis...
Uh...
...For just $1.99 a minute.
That's a steal
because I'm a great pal.
Uh...
We could talk
about sports or barbecue.
[ Grunts ]
Jerry, get a job.